<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.1.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://ex0dus-0x.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://ex0dus-0x.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2016-02-21T12:20:55-05:00</updated><id>http://ex0dus-0x.github.io/</id><title>./codemuch?</title><subtitle>Personal site and blog for the teaching and spreading of hacktivism and programming and everything technical</subtitle><entry><title>How to be the World’s Best Hacktivist</title><link href="http://ex0dus-0x.github.io/2016/02/20/how-to-be-the-worlds-best-hacktivist/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to be the World&#39;s Best Hacktivist" /><published>2016-02-20T07:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2016-02-20T07:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://ex0dus-0x.github.io/2016/02/20/how-to-be-the-worlds-best-hacktivist</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://ex0dus-0x.github.io/2016/02/20/how-to-be-the-worlds-best-hacktivist/">&lt;p&gt;OK, first off, I&#39;m not from Anonymous. Of course, I respect this group for their commitment and worldwide diffusion of their hacktivist ethos.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; After putting that aside, I would like to say that I am quite proud of my skill in penetration testing. I hope to have a successful career in penetration testing, computer security, and even a hacktivist at night! I also hope you the best, aspiring hacker-reader, in your journey in learning the art of hacking and intrusion. I wish to help you the best I can (Project idea: IRC?????) and spread my 4-years of learning hacking/penetration testing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt; First things first...&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a nice set of morals I follow every day. I am not a black hat, nor a script kiddy, and I abide by these set of rules (which is ironic, since hackers &lt;i&gt;break&lt;/i&gt; rules. I hope that you will, with your integrity, follow mine, or even your own set of values and be truthful and live by it, like a real revolutionary hero is like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Hacking isn&#39;t a superpower. It is an art, a sacred practice. I&#39;m not trying to sound like Confucius, but do not take advantage of a new profound skill, in a bad and negative way. This means &lt;b&gt;DO NOT BE A BLACKHAT!&lt;/b&gt; You are a hacktivist, a combination of hacker and activist, and as one, you are also taking upon the role of a hero, a symbol.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Hackers are creatorsYou aren&#39;t a hacker if you just learned how to deface a site, or backdoor a server. A hacker possesses many traits. Most respectable hacktivists I know are courageous, selfless, and ready to do anything for their cause. They do not give up, and with their profound skill, think outside the box. I remember one the public library&#39;s database was flawed. Not  because of a certain exploit, but a human flaw, where their password was a 4-digit PIN. Through figuring out this flaw I generated a wordlist of all 4 digit numeric characters possible (from 0000 to 9999) and once I obtained a username, was able to crack it with Burp Suite. &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;Don&#39;t be a script kiddy. Hackers are studious (but they do shit in school, no surprise there) and dedicate their lives to studying every aspect of computer science, programming, hacking, social engineering, electronics, etc. An example that I see A LOT is the DoS attack. Executing one is SO easy, and it requires 3 steps. 1. Get LOIC 2. Obtain the person that pissed you off on Xbox&#39;s IP through a grabber (sniffer, I guess is the &quot;politically correct term&quot;) 3. Click IMMA CHARGIN MY LASER. There, you are now a member of Anonymous because you sent a tremendous amount of data to one&#39;s router. Also, in relation to script kiddies, do not get into argument. Script Kiddy: IMMA BOOT YOUR FUCKING ASS OFF THE INTERNET. Don&#39;t fight them. Don&#39;t threaten. Reason with them, but assert yourself as a person that is smarter and more mature. &lt;/li&gt; 
 &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Programming&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; One thing people always asked me was where to start. I believe that it is up to them, but I always think that the best way was to learn the fundamentals. People always are eager to learn, and they yet end up on the wrong step of the path, and can really screw things up. You have to have a good foundation of knowledge, that makes you technical, as well as help you learn more advanced subjects faster, and more efficiently. For example, after learning python, I was able to understand code in Python, and because of this, was able to configure the source code for a pentesting tool to fit my needs. What languages do I recommend? Thanks you asking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; HTML - &lt;i&gt; HTML, or Hyper Text Markup Language, is the code that is used to write websites. I am currently writing this article in HTML. This is a very easy language, and I learned it not even in a week, but a few days. I learned it to write websites, but if you are wondering why it has use for hacking, it enables you to help understand the anatomy of a site more, such as when you are conducting a SQL Injection, or even just looking at a webpage to look for any vector to launch to an attack. Alongside HTML is CSS, which is used to simply make sites look pretty (like Bootstrap.css, which made this site pretty) and Javascript, which is used to add interactivity to the site, such as buttons, animations, etc.&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python - &lt;i&gt;I believe that this is the easiest and most useful programming language ever created. It is very VERY usefuland resourceful, and is &quot;batteries included&quot;, meaning that it comes with its own IDE (Integrated Development Environment). The code is very easy to learn and comprehend, and is the language recommended for all beginners.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Next...&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;READ.&lt;/b&gt;To learn, you have to learn to read. &lt;a href=&quot;texts.html&quot;&gt;Suggested Readings&lt;/a&gt; provide some of my favorite books, ones that you&#39;ll like as well. Some books on programming are there as well. There really isn&#39;t other ways to learn. If you are a visual learner, videos may work out for you, such as when I was learning code. I used both resources and it helped me effectively learn code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C|EH, or Certified Ethical Hacker All-In-One, is a very good book for beginners that is also technical, and widely used as a textbook. It introduces you to everything basic in hacking, and with this fundamental knowledge, you can move on to more advanced things. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;After...&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep in mind that reading isn&#39;t the only thing you should be doing. Theory is great, but application is better. Take what you learned, and play around. Let&#39;s say I learned how to write a basic number-counting program in C++. Using my knowledge of loops and flow control, I can make more whimsical programs. Maybe I wanted to incorporate something to do with hacking. Doing a bit research on Stackexchange can help me learn about exploit building, and such. Knowledge is a great thing. This is what seperates the script kiddies and the real hackers. Hackers want to learn, and to add on to their knowledge. Script kiddies want to learn, but not for their knowledge but just for their destructive behavior. Hackers utilize this knowledge to invent. Script kiddies utilize this knowledge to fuck up. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; And other thing I want to put out there: people tend to believe that if you are a hacker who uses &quot;d0xers&quot; or &quot;booters&quot; you are automatically a script kiddy. In a way that seems like it, but it goes back to the point I made about knowledge. I know MANY hackers, very prestigious ones, I have add, who utilize these &quot;unconventional&quot; tools. As long as you have an understanding of what you are doing, then it is OK. Don&#39;t get me wrong, I have a Kali Linux book that teaches you how to use LOIC. If you know what you are doing, and maybe even understand how the program is written and how to &lt;b&gt;ADD ON&lt;/b&gt; to it, it is fine. Using tools isn&#39;t a weakness. It&#39;s to help aid you in the learning process, and is the step before you learn how to write your own, etc. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Wrap-Up&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Thank you for reading! This is my 2nd article. I do not know how many readers I have so far, but if you are sticking around to read them, thank you, and I really appreciate it. I hope this blog goes beyond a humble and measly readership and reaches a large population of people, since this is my passion, and I want to help others learn and keep informed. Stay tuned for my next article!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ex0dus</name></author><summary>OK, first off, I&#39;m not from Anonymous. Of course, I respect this group for their commitment and worldwide diffusion of their hacktivist ethos.
 After putting that aside, I would like to say that I am quite proud of my skill in penetration testing. I hope to have a successful career in penetration testing, computer security, and even a hacktivist at night! I also hope you the best, aspiring hacker-reader, in your journey in learning the art of hacking and intrusion. I wish to help you the best I can (Project idea: IRC?????) and spread my 4-years of learning hacking/penetration testing.
 First things first...
Here is a nice set of morals I follow every day. I am not a black hat, nor a script kiddy, and I abide by these set of rules (which is ironic, since hackers break rules. I hope that you will, with your integrity, follow mine, or even your own set of values and be truthful and live by it, like a real revolutionary hero is like.

 Hacking isn&#39;t a superpower. It is an art, a sacred practice. I&#39;m not trying to sound like Confucius, but do not take advantage of a new profound skill, in a bad and negative way. This means DO NOT BE A BLACKHAT! You are a hacktivist, a combination of hacker and activist, and as one, you are also taking upon the role of a hero, a symbol.
 Hackers are creatorsYou aren&#39;t a hacker if you just learned how to deface a site, or backdoor a server. A hacker possesses many traits. Most respectable hacktivists I know are courageous, selfless, and ready to do anything for their cause. They do not give up, and with their profound skill, think outside the box. I remember one the public library&#39;s database was flawed. Not  because of a certain exploit, but a human flaw, where their password was a 4-digit PIN. Through figuring out this flaw I generated a wordlist of all 4 digit numeric characters possible (from 0000 to 9999) and once I obtained a username, was able to crack it with Burp Suite. 
 Don&#39;t be a script kiddy. Hackers are studious (but they do shit in school, no surprise there) and dedicate their lives to studying every aspect of computer science, programming, hacking, social engineering, electronics, etc. An example that I see A LOT is the DoS attack. Executing one is SO easy, and it requires 3 steps. 1. Get LOIC 2. Obtain the person that pissed you off on Xbox&#39;s IP through a grabber (sniffer, I guess is the &quot;politically correct term&quot;) 3. Click IMMA CHARGIN MY LASER. There, you are now a member of Anonymous because you sent a tremendous amount of data to one&#39;s router. Also, in relation to script kiddies, do not get into argument. Script Kiddy: IMMA BOOT YOUR FUCKING ASS OFF THE INTERNET. Don&#39;t fight them. Don&#39;t threaten. Reason with them, but assert yourself as a person that is smarter and more mature.  
 
Programming
 One thing people always asked me was where to start. I believe that it is up to them, but I always think that the best way was to learn the fundamentals. People always are eager to learn, and they yet end up on the wrong step of the path, and can really screw things up. You have to have a good foundation of knowledge, that makes you technical, as well as help you learn more advanced subjects faster, and more efficiently. For example, after learning python, I was able to understand code in Python, and because of this, was able to configure the source code for a pentesting tool to fit my needs. What languages do I recommend? Thanks you asking.

 HTML -  HTML, or Hyper Text Markup Language, is the code that is used to write websites. I am currently writing this article in HTML. This is a very easy language, and I learned it not even in a week, but a few days. I learned it to write websites, but if you are wondering why it has use for hacking, it enables you to help understand the anatomy of a site more, such as when you are conducting a SQL Injection, or even just looking at a webpage to look for any vector to launch to an attack. Alongside HTML is CSS, which is used to simply make sites look pretty (like Bootstrap.css, which made this site pretty) and Javascript, which is used to add interactivity to the site, such as buttons, animations, etc.

Python - I believe that this is the easiest and most useful programming language ever created. It is very VERY usefuland resourceful, and is &quot;batteries included&quot;, meaning that it comes with its own IDE (Integrated Development Environment). The code is very easy to learn and comprehend, and is the language recommended for all beginners.

Next...
READ.To learn, you have to learn to read. Suggested Readings provide some of my favorite books, ones that you&#39;ll like as well. Some books on programming are there as well. There really isn&#39;t other ways to learn. If you are a visual learner, videos may work out for you, such as when I was learning code. I used both resources and it helped me effectively learn code.
C|EH, or Certified Ethical Hacker All-In-One, is a very good book for beginners that is also technical, and widely used as a textbook. It introduces you to everything basic in hacking, and with this fundamental knowledge, you can move on to more advanced things. 
After...
Keep in mind that reading isn&#39;t the only thing you should be doing. Theory is great, but application is better. Take what you learned, and play around. Let&#39;s say I learned how to write a basic number-counting program in C++. Using my knowledge of loops and flow control, I can make more whimsical programs. Maybe I wanted to incorporate something to do with hacking. Doing a bit research on Stackexchange can help me learn about exploit building, and such. Knowledge is a great thing. This is what seperates the script kiddies and the real hackers. Hackers want to learn, and to add on to their knowledge. Script kiddies want to learn, but not for their knowledge but just for their destructive behavior. Hackers utilize this knowledge to invent. Script kiddies utilize this knowledge to fuck up. 
 And other thing I want to put out there: people tend to believe that if you are a hacker who uses &quot;d0xers&quot; or &quot;booters&quot; you are automatically a script kiddy. In a way that seems like it, but it goes back to the point I made about knowledge. I know MANY hackers, very prestigious ones, I have add, who utilize these &quot;unconventional&quot; tools. As long as you have an understanding of what you are doing, then it is OK. Don&#39;t get me wrong, I have a Kali Linux book that teaches you how to use LOIC. If you know what you are doing, and maybe even understand how the program is written and how to ADD ON to it, it is fine. Using tools isn&#39;t a weakness. It&#39;s to help aid you in the learning process, and is the step before you learn how to write your own, etc. 
Wrap-Up
 Thank you for reading! This is my 2nd article. I do not know how many readers I have so far, but if you are sticking around to read them, thank you, and I really appreciate it. I hope this blog goes beyond a humble and measly readership and reaches a large population of people, since this is my passion, and I want to help others learn and keep informed. Stay tuned for my next article!</summary></entry><entry><title>Beginner’s Guide to Clean Code</title><link href="http://ex0dus-0x.github.io/2016/02/19/beginners-guide-to-clean-code/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Beginner&#39;s Guide to Clean Code" /><published>2016-02-19T07:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2016-02-19T07:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://ex0dus-0x.github.io/2016/02/19/beginners-guide-to-clean-code</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://ex0dus-0x.github.io/2016/02/19/beginners-guide-to-clean-code/">&lt;p&gt;What is the difference between &lt;b&gt;effective&lt;/b&gt; code and &lt;b&gt;clean&lt;/b&gt; code?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;Let&#39;s look at an example:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt; For some really weird reason, you want to print out &quot;Hello World&quot; five times in C++. This is what you write:
&lt;pre&gt;
int main(){
	std::cout &amp;gt;&amp;gt; &quot;Hello World!&quot; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; std::endl;
	std::cout &amp;gt;&amp;gt; &quot;Hello World!&quot; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; std::endl;
	std::cout &amp;gt;&amp;gt; &quot;Hello World!&quot; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; std::endl;
	std::cout &amp;gt;&amp;gt; &quot;Hello World!&quot; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; std::endl;
	std::cout &amp;gt;&amp;gt; &quot;Hello World!&quot; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; std::endl;
} &lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Of course, you wouldn&#39;t do that. You would instead use:
&lt;pre&gt;
int main(){
	for( i = 5; i &amp;gt;= 0; i-- ){
		std::cout &amp;gt;&amp;gt; &quot;Hello World!&quot; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; std::endl;
	}
} &lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; This is &lt;b&gt;effective&lt;/b&gt; code. Even though this is a really basic example, it still demonstrates how we can write code, but shorter, easier, and
doesn&#39;t require me to press &lt;code&gt;Ctrl+V&lt;/code&gt; 5 times. But what is the idea of &lt;b&gt; clean &lt;/b&gt; code? &lt;b&gt; Clean &lt;/b&gt; code looks &lt;i&gt;professional.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Clean&lt;/b&gt;
code is &lt;i&gt;formal&lt;/i&gt;. &lt;b&gt; Clean &lt;/b&gt; code, when examined by other programmers, is &lt;i&gt;undestandable&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;replicable&lt;/i&gt; and has a &lt;i&gt;steady flow&lt;/i&gt; where the programmer is easily to able to read through it without scratching his or her head and saying, &lt;i&gt;&quot;Huh?&quot;&lt;/i&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Let us look at my criteria for clean code.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;1. &lt;i&gt;//Comment&lt;/i&gt; everything! &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Code are like directions, that are pretty indecipherable, especially if you have written &lt;i&gt;alot&lt;/i&gt; of it.
Shouldn&#39;t it be pretty logical to have comments, and give a human interpretation of what is happening? Not only should you write comments, but you should also make your comments, short, decipherable and does not overly explain what you are doing. Let&#39;s look at S. Kiddy&#39;s code:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
#So here is my code. I am going to first declare the variable x, and then give it the value of 5. 
#After that, I will add 7 to x, and then call x again, and I will get 12. 
&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; x = 5
&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; x + 7
&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; x
&amp;gt; 12
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt; It&#39;s good that at least he is commenting what he is doing, but it does not mean that it is &lt;b&gt;clean&lt;/b&gt;. The comments are overly explaining what is happening. Let&#39;s look at Masta Haxa&#39;s code: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
#Declare variable x with value of 5. Add 7 to it, and call x to have value of 12.
&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; x = 5
&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; x + 7
&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; x
&amp;gt; 12	
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt; The program is the same, but the commenting is &lt;b&gt;simple&lt;/b&gt; and still explains the concept of the code in a whole. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;2. Whitespace &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; The concept of &lt;b&gt;whitespace&lt;/b&gt; is pretty big in programming, especially object-oriented. Although it is NOT a requirement, people tend to enjoy looking at code that is not tightly packed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
for( x = 3; x &amp;lt; 4; x++){
	cout &amp;lt;&amp;lt; &quot;Wow! This is pretty spaced out&quot; &amp;lt;&amp;lt; endl;
}&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compared to something like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
for(x=3;x&amp;lt;4;x++){
	cout&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&quot;helpmeimtrapped&quot;&amp;lt;&amp;lt; endl;
	}
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;3.Indentation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indentation, like whitespace is another form of organization. Also known as &lt;b&gt;indent style&lt;/b&gt; it will easily help one recognize
your code due to positioning, as well as for you, when you come back to edit your code. This is especially important for writing code in HTML. Let me demonstrate:

&lt;img src=&quot;/img/indentation.png&quot; /&gt;	
				
&lt;p&gt; In this situation, my code is neatly indented. I am able to navigate, and I include (a bit) of comments. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; This is an example of code that has &lt;b&gt;NO&lt;/b&gt; indentation (img source: http://bit.ly/1ZmLVLz) &lt;/p&gt;
				

&lt;img src=&quot;/img/notindentation.png&quot; /&gt;
				
&lt;h2 class=&quot;section-heading&quot;&gt;4.Variable Name Declaration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt; When you have a variable, class, structure, or any of that sort, is it not logical to name it something relevant. Give your variables ,classes, objects, etc. concise names. This shows organization and unity in your code. If you are writing code in an object-oriented programming language, such as C++, this is very important especially working with inheritance and stuff like that. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt; //Good example
struct PERSON{ //PERSON struct type
	int age;
	string name;
	float weight
}familymember; //Define object for PERSON type
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt; and here&#39;s a &lt;b&gt;BAD&lt;/b&gt; example &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;
//I will make a program where the user will input a number, and the computer returns that number + 2. 
//Here are my variables:
int noodles;
cin &amp;gt;&amp;gt; noodles;
noodles + 2;
cout &amp;lt;&amp;lt; noodles &amp;lt;&amp;lt; endl;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Shouldn&#39;t it be a little more logical to call the variable &quot;input&quot; instead? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Thank you for reading my first article! I will be coming up with more in the future, but this one was definitely O.K. There are, of course &lt;b&gt; ALOT &lt;/b&gt; of things you can do to improve your code and make it &lt;b&gt; clean &lt;/b&gt; and &lt;b&gt; effective &lt;/b&gt;. Code review, although I did not include it in here, is obviously a must, and an amateur programmer like you and me, &lt;b&gt; WILL &lt;/b&gt; always have questions. One of the best places is StackExchange, a prominent Q&amp;amp;A forum community. Visit at: http://stackexchange.com/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>ex0dus</name></author><summary>What is the difference between effective code and clean code?</summary></entry></feed>
